Guide to the Records of the Alternative Media Center and and Interactive Telecommunications Program, Tisch School of the Arts RG.35.2
New York University Archives
Records of the Alternative Media Center and Interactive Telecommunications Program, Tisch School of the Arts
1973-2018, ongoing
New York University Archives
New York University. Interactive Telecommunications Program
RG.35.2
20 Linear Feet (19 Paige boxes)
4 websites in 4 archived websites.
The Alternative Media Center and Interactive Telecommunications Program were established within Tisch School of the Arts in 1971. This collection contains the administrative records of the Alternative Media Collection, archived websites of their journal ADJACENT, photographs and slides of AMC related events, and thesis projects completed by students in the Interactive Telecommunications Program. The formats of the thesis projects include paper, VHS, CD, DVD, U-Matic, Floppy Disc, Zip Discs, and Hi 8 Tapes.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the records of Tisch School of the Art's Alternative Media Center and Interactive Telecommunications Program. The collection spans the early 1970s, when the Alternative Media Center was first established, through 2012 and contains administrative records, correpondence, publications, thesis projects, issues of ADJACENT, and photographic materials.
The majority of the materials in the collection are thesis projects completed by students in the Interactive Telecommunications Program which was established in 1979. Approximately half of the theses are paper documents, while the other half range in format from VHS, mini-DV, CD, DVD, U-Matic, Hi 8 tape, Floppy Disc, and Zip Disc. In addition, the series of photographic materials contains prints, slides, and negatives.
History of the Alternative Media Center and Interactive Telecommunications Program
The Alternative Media Center was established within the Tisch School of the Arts at New York University in 1971 by professors George C. Stoney and Red Burns. After co-teaching a video production course focused on the use of video in a community-based context, Stoney and Burns co-founded the AMC and began their work training citizens in the tools of video production for what would eventually become Public-Access television. Both Stoney and Burns were documentary filmmakers and Stoney is referred to as the "father of public-access television."
The early 1970s saw significant developments in technology and media, including the then-new tool of portable video made possible by the creation of Sony's "Portapak" and Apple II computers. The AMC was created with a focus on exploring this new technology and to serve as a pioneering center for application development and field trials. Through the AMC, Stoney, Burns, and their colleagues worked to make significant developments in their fields of documentary film and traditional media. This included lobbying Congress for the creation of what is now public access cable television and significant field trials for two-way television in community settings, the use of Teletext in major urban centers and communications technologies for the developmentally disabled.
Professor Burns believed a graduate course of study was needed for new media developers, and in 1979 the Interactive Telecommunications Program developed as a graduate department focused on the study and design of new media and social applications. In 1983 Professor Burns was appointed Chair of the ITP department and maintained the position until 2010.
Arrangement
This collection is separated into five series each of which is arranged alphabetically, chronologically, or in accordance with its original order.
Series I: Administrative Records of the Alternative Media Center is arranged alphabetically
Series II: Alternative Media Center Publications and Papers is arranged according to its original order
Series III: Interactive Telecommunications Program Theses is arranged into two subseries, Subseries A: Thesis Projects -- Paper and Subseries B: Thesis Projects -- Audio/Visual Formats, both of which are arranged chronologically by the year the project was completed
Series IV: Photographic Materials is arranged according to its original order.
Series V: Adjacent is arranged according to its original order.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Unprocessed materials are not available to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In 2018, https://itp.nyu.edu/adjacent/ was selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In December 2022, https://adjacent-rituals.itp.io/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.006. In December 2023, https://adjacent-ecoscope.itp.io/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.003. In January 2025, https://itp.nyu.edu/adjacent_classic/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2025.004.
Theses.; Telecommunication.; Burns, Red
- Series I: Administrative Records of the Alternative Media Center, 1973-2003, undated
  - Academic Report to Dean, 1988, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alternate Media Center, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - AMC Meeting Notes and Memoranda, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - American Express, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Apple -- Bruce Prevo, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Apple Computer Inc., 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Apple -- Developer Information 1994-95, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Apple -- Design Contest, 1987-1988, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Apple -- Open House 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Applications -- Class of 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Applications -- Class of 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art Directors Club, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Art/Science Panel, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aspen Institute, 1992, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AT&T Foundation, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Avnet, Mark (Scholarships), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barney, Matthew, 1995, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bates, Margaret, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - BCTV (1 of 2), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - BCTV (2 of 2), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Belagio, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bell Atlantic, 1997, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Berks Community Television (BCTV), 1986, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bernstein, Nina, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Big Picture, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Black Students in New Media, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bitonati, Matt, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brera, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brookings Institution, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Budget Policy Advisory, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Campbell, Mary Schmidt, 1992-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cantor Film Center, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - CAT GRANT -- NY State (1 of 2), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - CAT GRANT -- NY State (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Chadhuri, Una, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Commodore, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Computer Channel, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Computer Science Multimedia, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Connors Communication, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Corbis, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Crains, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - CRB Foundation, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Creative Capital, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Crossover Technologies, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Dee, Elliot, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Demac, Donna, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Denise Caruso Articles -- NY Times, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Dentsu Institute for Human Studies, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Department of Health, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Development Office, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Digital Arts Center NYC, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Digital F/X Inc., 1988, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Digital Renaissance, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dutch Electronic Art Festival, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Edwin Schlossberg Incorporated -- ECHO, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Elton, Martin, 1975-1976, 1980, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Enrollment Goals, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Estate Project (Artists with AIDS), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Evans, Eli, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Executive Enterprises, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Eyebeam Atelier, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Fabrica, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Faculty Meetings, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Faculty Working Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Fellowships, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Financial Aid Policy, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Five Year Plan, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Forbes Magazine, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Fund for the City of New York, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Furmanski, Philip, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - FYI, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Gallatin School, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Getting Real, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Globe.com, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Governor's Task Force on New Media and the Internet, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Greer, Heather, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Guidelines for Responding to Student Related Problems, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Gurl, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Harlem Cybercafe, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Harlem School of the Arts, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Hashimoto, Minoru, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Helsinki University of Art, 1992-1993, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Heritage Project -- CRB Foundation, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Heydebrand, Wolf, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Heyman, George, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hippocrates, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - History, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Horn, Stacy, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Hundley, James, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - iBeam Broadcasting, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - IBM, 1990-1992, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - IBM Multimedia Lab, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - ICA -- International Communications Association, 1988-1997, bulk 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - I.D. -- The International Design Magazine, 1993, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - IICS -- International Interactive Communications Society, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - IMA -- Interactive Multimedia Association, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Independent Television Commission, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Innovative Design Lab of Samsung (IDS), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - International Film Festival (Rotterdam), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - International Radio and Television Society, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - International Visitors Program, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Interval Research Corporation, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Interval Research Workshop, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Itau Cultural, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - James, Debra, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jefferson, Kris, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Julie, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Johnson, Steven, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Kelly, Chris, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kincade, Douglas (Princeton U.), 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kleiner, Art, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Kurtz, Mara, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Kuramata, Shiro, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Lanier, Jaron, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Levine, Michael A., 1995, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lipton, Bartnett, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Lotos Club, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lucent Technologies, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Macromedia, 1992, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Manhattan High Schools, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mannes, George, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Markle Foundation, 1989-1998, bulk 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Matrix Awards -- April 14, 1997, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Mayor's Award for Red Burns, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Mayor's Council on New Media, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - McMillan, Marilyn, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Media Archive Center, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Media Lab Europe, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Media Lab Europe Limited, 2000 October 25 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Medical School Task Force, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Microsoft -- 1993-94, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Microsoft Account, 1993, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Microsoft -- Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Mid-Atlantic Arts Foundation, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - MILIA, 1994-1997, bulk 1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mills, Michael, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Moki, Jin Ja, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Morgan, J.P., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Murray, Janet (MIT), 1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Museum Digitial Library, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art (MOCA), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Museum of Television and Radio, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Nadworny, Laura, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Naimark, Michael, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - National Design Musuem, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - National Magazine Awards, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - National Museum of Women in Arts, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Narvaez, Christine, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - NCR, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Neighborhood Web Project, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Networked Entertainment World (NEW), 1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - New Medat at the Millennium, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - New Media Book Project, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1995, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - New York City Economic Development Corporation, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - New York City Investment Fund, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - New York Hall of Science, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - New York New Media Association -- Internship Program, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - New York University -- Graduate Forum, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - New York Women In Communications, Inc. (NYWICI), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Nice Letters, 1988-1992, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Nomura Research Insitute, Ltd., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - NTT, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - NYC Partnership and Chamber of Commerce, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NYNEX -- Account Closing Papers, 1993-1994, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - NYNEX -- Budget, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - NYNEX -- Contract Info. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - NYNEX -- Contract Info. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - NYNEX -- Contract Info. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - NYNEX -- Contract Info. 1994 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - NYNEX -- Contract Info. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - NYNEX -- Contract Info. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - NYNEX -- Descriptions 1992 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - NYNEX -- Descriptions 1993 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - NYNEX -- Descriptions 1994 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - NYNEX -- Descriptions 1995 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - NYNEX -- GA Appointments, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - NYNEX -- Independent Contractors, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - NYNEX -- Miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - O'Hara, Pat, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Oppenheim, Dean David, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Patent Claim -- Gnostech 93-94, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - PC Forum, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Proposals, 1989-1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Public Policy Notes, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - RAND, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Razorfish, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Reading Consortium -- Addresses, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reading Consortium -- Agendas, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reading Consortium -- Area Plan on Aging, 1975 April 17 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reading Consortium -- Berks Community Television, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Reading Consortium -- Budget, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reading Consortium -- Conferences, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Reading Consortium -- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reading Consortium -- Diary, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reading Consortium -- Implementation, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Reading Consortium -- Internal Memos, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reading Consortium -- Minutes/Meetings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Reading Consortium -- National Science Foundation, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Reading Consortium -- Press Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Reading Consortium -- Statement of Purpose, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Reading Consortium -- Tasks, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - ReadSpeak, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations, 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ritchin, Fred, 1993, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Report to the Dean (Notes), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Reuters, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Robinowitz, Stuart, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rosenbaum, Steven -- BNN TV, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Roundtable in Multimedia, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Rozin, Danny, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Rudin Foundation, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rushkoff, Douglas, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Summer Institute in Academic Multimedia, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Summer Institute in Academic Multimedia -- Accepted Proposals, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Summer Institute in Academic Multimedia -- Contract, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Summer Institute in Academic Multimedia -- Proposal, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sun Donation, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Sun Microsystems, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Access Workbook -- Volume I: Resources and Information (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - The Access Workbook -- Volume I: Resources and Information (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Time Warner, 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Time Warner -- Budget Memos, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Time Warner Lab, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Time Warner Media Lab, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Viacom, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Viacom Donation, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - World of Wonder, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - YORB -- 1994-95, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - YORB -- 1994-95 -- Slides, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - YORB -- 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - YORB -- Budget Memos, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - YORB -- Electronic Neighborhood, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - YORB -- UPS Claim, March 1997 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Series II: Alternative Media Center Publications and Papers, 1974-1986, undated
  - Teletext Information Services on Public Television - Phase I, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Teletext Proposal - Draft, 1981 October 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Report 2: Gannett Videotex, 1982 May (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Teletext -- Research, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Managing Subjective Reactions to Teletext Page Design, 1981 September (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Teletext -- Proposals, 1979, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Teletext Field Trial -- Production Operations, 1983 January (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Teletext Field Trial -- Technical Background and Issues, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Research on Broadcast Teletext: Working Paper Number Three, 1981 December (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Interaction Between Use of Teletext and Viewing of Television: Final Report to the Corporation of Public Broadcasting, 1983 May (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Telecommunications and Service to the Developmentally Disabled -- Volume I: Needs and Opportunities, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Telecommunications and Service to the Developmentally Disabled -- Volume II: Application Possibilities, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Telecommunications and Service to the Developmentally Disabled -- Volume III: Decisions on Demonstration Projects, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Effect of Current Economic Pressures on the Scope for New Telecommunications Services in the Field of Developmental Disabilities, 1981 July (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Production Opertaions at the Alternative Media Center/WETA-TV Teletext Field Trial in Washington, D.C., 1983 January (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Implementing Interactive Telecommunications Services, 1979 October (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - National Networking Among UAPS: A Pilot Test of Electronic Mail, 1979 November (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Telecommunications Applied to University Affiliated Programs, 1978 August 15 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Making Telecommunications Work for the Developmentally Disabled, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - National Networking Among UAPS: A Telecommunications Demonstration, 1980 January (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - A Manual for UAF ONTYME Message System Users, 1979 November (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Six Lessons in Electronic Entertainment, 1982 March (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Experiment in Urban Telecommunications -- Phase II Solicitation 74-8 [3 copies], 1975 May (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - An Introduction to Telemedicine, 1974 June (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Videotex in Canada: A Working Paper on the Study of Social Impact, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - AMC -- Proposals and Working Paper Responses, 1979 May (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Using Videotape as a Clinical Tool, 1985 May 2 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Introduction to Videodisc Systems, Production, and Market Development, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Telecommunications Topics, Second Edition, 1978 March (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - The Telecommunications Market of the Eighties, 1981 October 19 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Test and Evaluation of Public Service Uses of Cable Television: Reading, Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Telecommunications and Developmentally Disabled People, 1981 July (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Final Report: Gannett Videotex, 1982 July 23 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Videotex Update, 1982 July 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Simulating Reality in Computer Images: Lessons from Art and Cognitive Science, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Psychological Theories of Aesthetics: Implications for Display Design and Evaluation, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Measuring Subjective Reactions to Teletext Page Design, 1981 September (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Communications, Computers and Human Settlements, 1980 March 19-21 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The NYU-Reading Consortium -- Progress Report, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Public Access Experience: Profiles of Six Centers, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Reading Consortium -- Public Service and Interactive Television, 1976 Jauary (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Planning a Pilot Broadcast Teletext Service for Public Television, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)